As we saw in the previous set of topics,
containment uses the in keyword to
determine whether a value is in a list of values.
Containment is important when one needs to know,
for example, if an answer someone entered
for a question is in an acceptable list of
answers. For example, in this 146-containment
file, we have a list of ancient civilizations
stored in a variable with that name on line
1. Line 3 has a print statement to see if
Egypt is one of the ancient civilizations.
On line 4, Japan is tested, and on line 5,
China is tested. I will run this code, and
we see that Egypt and China return true,
but Japan returns false, which is to be expected
given the list of ancient civilizations on line
1. In programming, many keywords that determine
a true or false value can have the word not added
to look for an opposite result. A person may be
asked to enter a territory not part of an ancient
civilization. To test this not keyword, I will add
the word not in front of the in keyword on line 5,
rerun the code, and now for our third
test for China, we see a value of false,
as this statement of China not being in the list
of ancient civilizations is indeed false. We have
reached the end of this topic, so it is time for
another review. Use this code file, 146-analyze,
to answer the questions on lines 4, 7, 9, and
11, without running the code. In the next video,
I will reveal the answers and recap
what we have covered in this topic.